# KELLY **NGUYEN**

I'm a software engineer based out of Austin, Texas. I build robust websites and applications, with a focus on front-end React development. I am in love with creating and designing memorable user experiences, bringing aesthetic pleasure and functionality together.

.....

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Full Stack Javascript - Austin Coding Academy - Jan 2019 - Sept 2019

Data Analyst - Fresenius Medical Care - June 2019 - Present

Quality Data Entry - Fresenius Medical Care - Aug 2017 - June 2019

Administrative Assistant - Shell Oil & Gas Company - June 2012 - Aug 2013

**DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS** 

Brewery App - CSS • JS • JSX • React

Daimler Trucks - HTML • CSS • JS • Meteor • Al Tech

CarePortal - HTML • Bootstrap • JS • Node.js • Handlebars

Austin Coding Academy - HTML • CSS • JS • React

Fresenius Medical Care - SQL • PowerBl

## I love problem solving, which is exactly what I do when I

- Create and implement various UI features and enhancements on **CarePortal**, an app that placed **first** in a community hackathon
- Implemented UI designs for the Daimler Truck Hackathon application
- Develop multiple dashboards in **PowerBI** pulling in custom **SQL** queries at Fresenius
- Built a SPA prototype that allows users to input their location that will filter out selections to nearby options using React/Redux, Express, and MongoDB

# I also have a strong sense for creativity and seeing "the big picture", which allowed me to

- Generate new concepts and develop fresh designs for applications
- Provide valuable insights when analyzing data and code with a strong power of observation
- Take on challenging tasks and develop creative solutions through critical thinking

### **EDUCATION**

**Austin Coding Academy -** 2019 Full Stack Web Development

**University of Texas at Austin -** 2017 BS, Nutrition and Health

### **TECHNICAL**

- HTML5/CSS3
- JavaScript ES6
- ReactJS
- Redux
- Node.js
- Express
- Git / Github
- MongoDB
- SQL
- ¡Query, AJAX, APIs
- Bootstrap
- Materialize

### CONTACT

📤 Austin, TX

linkedin.com/in/kellynguyen617

https://github.com/kelly-tnguyen

■ nguyen.kelly617@gmail.com

**(832) 638 - 7040**